Blood is a chord that resonates through time.
The Piano Lesson is a drama, music film directed by Malcolm Washington.
A brother and sister's battle over a prized heirloom piano unleashes haunting truths
about how the past is perceived — and who defines a family legacy.
Boy Willie, played by John David Washington.
Berniece Charles, played by Danielle Deadwyler.
Doaker Charles, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Lymon, played by Ray Fisher.
Wining Boy, played by Michael Potts.
Avery, played by Corey Hawkins.
The Piano Lesson is a 2024 American drama film directed by Malcolm
Washington, who co-wrote the screenplay with Virgil Williams.
It is an adaptation of the 1987 Pulitzer Prize-winning play by August Wilson.
It stars an ensemble cast of Samuel L.
Jackson, John David Washington, Ray Fisher, Michael Potts, Erykah Badu,
Skylar Aleece Smith, Danielle Deadwyler, and Corey Hawkins.
The Piano Lesson premiered at the 51st Telluride Film Festival on August 31, 2024, and it was released in select
theaters in the United States on November 8, 2024, before streaming on Netflix on November 22.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics.
Deadwyler was lauded for her performance, earning nominations for the Critics' Choice
Award and the Screen Actors Guild Award for Best Supporting Actress.
The film explores themes of heirloom, based on play
or musical, family, piano, 1930s.
The tone is emotional.